Israel is trying to trying to sway the
opinion of Israel among young people in
particular. All of the firms that have
been hired by Israel um in the last
month, which by the way, there's been
six of them, which is more than Israel
has hired under Farah in the previous
two years combined. Um, and most of
those firms have been hired in order to
target Gen Z, in order in order to
target um the the sector of the
population that is broken most sharply
in their support for Israel military
action.
Hi, I'm John Kuryaku and welcome back to
Deep Focus. In an explosive new article
published by the Quincy Institute for
Responsible Statecraft, the Israeli
government is spending $6 million for an
American firm to try to make Chat GPT
more pro-Israeli.
Clock Tower X, that's the name of the
company, will generate and deploy
content across platforms, help game
algorithms, plus manage AI frameworks to
make them more friendly to the Israeli
cause. With the American Israel Public
Affairs Committee,
also known as Apac, already wielding
more authority on Capitol Hill and in
political races all across the country,
how much more mindlessly pro- Israel
does the country need to be? We're going
to talk about this with the articles
author. Nick Cleveland Stout is a
research associate in the democratizing
foreign policy program at the Quincy
Institute for Responsible State Craft.
Previously, he conducted research on US
Brazil relations as a 2023 fullulbright
fellow at the federal university of
Santa Katarina with a particular focus
on the influence of American think tanks
in Brazil. Nick is also a former
Marcelus policy fellow with the John
Quincy Adams Society where he authored
the case for a green brack. His work has
appeared in responsible statecraft, The
Nation, The Intercept, the Brazilian
Report, Inkstick, and In the National
Interest. So, Nick, thank you for
joining us. This is I I didn't expect to
see something like this until I saw your
article.
>> Yeah, great to be with you here, John.
Um yeah, I it it kind of shocked me too
because I think that this is especially
that chat GBT um angle is something
pretty new that we're seeing. I mean
people are starting to use chatbt
similar to they would a normal SEO like
Google. I mean I I have a lot of
friends. I do it myself sometimes.
>> Sure.
>> Where I'll go and ask it a certain
question. Um, and so the idea behind it,
you know, is is that next time someone
goes to Chachet and says, you know, uh,
tell me about, you know, is Israel
committing war crimes in Gaza? What's
happening on the ground there? People
have a lot of questions. You know, this
is something that, um, you know, they're
not letting reporters into Gaza. So,
it's really difficult to get accurate
information out there and it allows
Israel to frame a lot of the debate. So
when people go to chat GBT next time,
you know, because of this Fern's work,
maybe they'll they'll come across more
pro-Israel messaging.
>> Couple of things too about chat GBT that
I think are important. First of all, um
because it's constantly learning, uh it
sometimes lies.
>> It won't say if you ask it a question
and it doesn't know the answer, it won't
say, "I don't know the answer." It'll
give you what it thinks might be the
answer. uh when when it first uh was
made public, I went on chat GPT and
said, "Who is John Kiryaku?" And it
said, "John Kuryaku is a former CIA
officer, a whistleblower on the CIA's
torture program, etc., etc. He graduated
from the University of Maryland
and earned a master's degree in peace
studies at the University of Bruge,
Belgium." Okay. I couldn't even find the
University of Maryland. I've never been
there. I certainly didn't graduate from
the University of Maryland. And I've
never been to Bruge, Belgium. I've never
studied peace studies. And I didn't even
know there was a university there. So I
went back on PT and I said, "You are
incorrect.
John Kiryaku earned a bachelor's degree
in Middle Eastern studies and a master's
degree in legislative affairs from
George Washington University." And then
Chad GPT came back and said, "No, you
are incorrect. John Kiryaku graduated
from University of Maryland and the
University of Bruge." So like I say, I
mean that's kind of funny. It's not, but
it is. It's constantly learning. Well,
what you say in your article, and I want
to read this because it's so important.
At least 80% of content Clock Tower
produces will be quote tailored to Gen Z
audiences across platforms,
including Tik Tok, Instagram, YouTube,
podcasts, and other relevant digital and
broadcast outlets with a minimum goal of
50 million impressions per month. Clock
Tower will even deploy websites and
content to deliver uh chat GPT framing
results on GPT conversations. In other
words, Clock Tower will create new
websites to influence how AI GPT models
such as Chat GPT, which are trained on
vast amounts of data from every corner
of the internet, frame topics and
respond to them, all on behalf of
Israel. So what you're saying here is
that this company is going to overwhelm
the internet with information in support
of Israel
just so that anytime somebody asks Chat
GPT a question about Israel, the
response is going to be pro-Israel. Is
that right?
>> Yeah, exactly. I mean, um, yeah, as Chad
already, as you say, like has all these
kinds of flukes and it and it repeats
this information very authoritatively.
Um, the way that it it's telling you
that you went to, uh, the University of
Brues, which by the way, I have been
there and it is a nice city. Um, so, you
know, I recommend adding it to your to
your bucket list even if um you didn't
have the privilege of attending
university there. Um, but yeah, it's
it's it's um it's really concerning and
and by the way, the person that um is
tasked with with carrying this out is a
guy by the name of Brad Parcale, who has
quite a bit of experience in running
these these kinds of campaigns um
engaging in all kinds of
>> like gorilla gorilla internet warfare
tactics,
>> right?
>> He was the uh Trump campaign manager,
was he not?
>> Yeah, exactly. He was the the former
Trump campaign manager um in in 2018 and
19 I believe or 19 and 20. And he had a
very public falling out with Trump
although seems to have reconciled in
some ways. Um but he was in 2016 when he
was working on the 2016 campaign. He was
also the Trump campaign official that
hired Cambridge Analytica um the firm
that was engaging in this kind of like
social media microargeting campaign. uh
and has been hired by a bunch of
different governments to help out with
with their elections. And um you know,
so Parcale is someone that is kind of at
the forefront of
employing new weapons of the internet um
against political uh enemies. And so in
this case, you know, Israel has hired
him uh on this $6 million contract with
by which by the way, I mean, I I see a
lot of contracts under the Foreign
Agents Registration Act, which is our
the US's foreign lobbying law, which is
really kind of just mostly a
transparency law in which you're able to
see um what different firms and American
lobbyists are doing on behalf of foreign
governments. And $6 million is is huge
by pretty much any metric. I mean there
are very few contracts that I've seen
that rise to that level. Um so so this
so you know this is very concerning and
it's the next iteration of this kind of
guerilla warfare taking place on the
internet. Um and so you know we'll we'll
see what what comes of it. But yeah
there's there's um there's all kinds of
things in this contract like it's not um
you know it's not just geared towards
training chatbt. There's also this
aspect of he Parcel is also he was
appointed earlier this this year um to
the to as an executive on the Salem
media network which is a conservative
Christian organization
um that produces a lot of very
well-known and influential podcasts
especially in conservative circles. It's
the one It's the It's the group that
produces the Charlie Kurt Show, the Hugh
Hewitt Show, The Right View with Laura
Trump. Um, a lot of a lot of podcasts
that are pretty influential, a lot of
radio shows, local radio shows. It's
it's this huge conglomeration. And part
of the contract actually,
um, that that that scale was hired under
for Israel is for him to integrate
pro-Israel messaging into um, this
conservative media network. And so he's
kind of wearing two hats at the same
time. I mean, he's an executive at this
media company, um, but he's also working
on behalf of Israel. And he's not even
really trying to hide the fact that
those are two separate things.
>> I I want you to speculate,
uh, for a minute, too, as to
as to what the uh what the end goal is.
Uh there was a poll that was released by
the Washington Post on the
5th of October uh where it said that for
the very first time a majority a
majority of American Jews believe
that Israel is committing genocide in
Gaza.
Is it to is the the whole purpose of
this to turn that around to to bring
back the unquestioning
pro- Israel sentiment of of a majority
of Americans? Is this shortterm? Is it
long-term? What are we looking at here?
>> Yeah, for for me, so um that's a
question that I've had too. And based on
the pattern that we've been seeing in
the new firms that are working on behalf
of Israel, to me the the answer is
actually pretty clear um that that
Israel is trying to trying to sway the
opinion of Israel among young people in
particular. all of the firms that have
been hired by Israel um in the last
month, which by the way, there's been
six of them, which is more than Israel
has hired under Farah in the previous
two years combined. Um and most of those
firms have been hired in order to target
Gen Z, in order in order to target um
the the sector of the population that is
broken most sharply in their support for
Israel military action. There was Yeah.
I mean, there's all kinds of polling
that's indicating that Israel is is
losing this support. I mean, there was a
Gallup poll from, I think, July that
found that only 9% of American adults
between the ages of 18 and 34 supported
Israel's military action in Gaza. Uh and
so they're clearly and you know instead
of changing their action instead of um
you know realizing why these
America's youth is breaking in support
which largely has to do with the
atrocities that that they're seeing with
their own two eyes. Instead of um
reconciling that and changing their
actions they've decided to go all in on
this strategy of trying to uh infiltrate
social media in particular. Um, I had
another article that came out a uh the
day after I published this one about
chatbt that that noted that Israel is
actually paying influencers that they
have, you know, we we see them, you
know, taking trips with influencers uh
to Israel to meet with BB Netanyahu, all
of these things. And we knew that a lot
of that was funded by Israel, but you
know, I found that that they're actually
the influencers are receiving uh checks
themselves in order to post on behalf of
Israel. Um, and the the invoice that I
found, it actually was pretty detailed
and it shows um, you know, how much how
many posts these influencers are
expected to to make per month um, and
and how much they're getting, all these
things. Uh, and I broke it down and I
estimated that it's, it's not really my
estimate, it's it's really what's under
Pharaoh. Um, that they're being paid
somewhere in the ballpark of between
$6,100 and $7,300
per post on social media platforms
presumably such as Tik Tok, Instagram,
which is a ton of money.
>> That's a lot of money.
>> Yeah, that's a great deal of money. Are
you seeing any other countries doing
this? I mean there are a lot of
countries especially in the Middle East
with a lot of money. The Saudis,
theQataris, the Kuwaitis, the Emiratis.
Are there any other countries that are
seeking to influence public opinion in
the United States among Gen Z?
>> Definitely. I mean I mean not in that
way currently that we know of um at
least that that I'm aware of. Um we did
see about I think it was this would have
been seven years ago now. Um Qatar did
have a operation. This was also um
somewhat similar in that they were they
were also paying influencers to um post
certain things, but a lot of it was
targeted towards
um not um not attacking um critics per
se, but trying to present Qatar as a
more moderate uh US ally. Um, so that's
really the only parallel that I can
think of, but what we're seeing here is
a little bit without precedent and
especially some of the guerilla warfare
tactics that we're seeing like the the
chat GPT aspect um and the astronomical
fees as well. I mean, I think that the
that $7,000 per post figure is so
astronomical because I mean, one foreign
countries uh are they're a client that
that is expected to pay a premium
already. I mean, if you look at like,
you know, what Exxon is paying, you
know, an American or or, you know, some
kind of what an American corporation is
paying to lobby um under the lobbying
disclosure act versus what any foreign
government um is paying under the
Foreign Agents Registration Act. There's
there there tends to be a disparity
there. you know, foreign governments
tend to have to pay a premium because
there is a certain reputational cost for
firms that register to represent these
um governments. Um and and then
secondly, obviously Israel is a very
controversial country. I mean um this UN
commission has said that it's committing
genocide. So um that's I think why the
that 7,000 figure is just so high. And I
should also add another layer to this
that I find somewhat concerning is that
the the firms that some of the firms
that have registered under Farah are
pretty um are pretty much ghosts online.
I mean it's hard to find much
information about uh who they are um
what what other work they do. I mean the
>> So we're not talking about the the the
big
>> established DC lobbying firms.
>> No, absolutely not. No. So that's Yeah.
I mean there might be one or two like
that that are representing Israel, but a
lot of them like um the Brad Parcel's
firm and then this other firm that's
paying influencers called Bridges
Partners. They both were created in the
last few months I believe. Um, and
there's there's no website for them.
There's no last I checked, there's no
LinkedIn page, no email, no press
contact. Um, so it's they're making it
very difficult to to for people to
contact them or for people to find
information out about them. Um, and so
there's a lot of question marks because
usually when I'm writing about foreign
lobbying, you know, I'm able to go to
the firm's website. I'm able to see um
you know the bios of the people that are
representing these people but but like
the the influencer contract for example
I can't even confirm the identity of the
people that are that are carrying that
out because there's no website with with
a bio or anything like that.
>> How do the Israelis gauge success in
something like this? Is it just by
looking at public opinion polls after
the fact?
>> Probably. I think um
yeah, I I imagine so. I imagine that's
that's certainly one metric of success.
I mean, I think that
you know, it's interesting that you
noted um in in part in that CHP BT
firm's case, Clock Tower X, the their
metric of success that they're going for
is impressions. um you know, 50 million
impressions per month, which I think
might sound like a lot to people that
are kind of outside of, you know, the
social media space, but like
realistically, if you're spending $6
million and you're only expecting to get
50 million impressions per month,
>> um
that's not 50 million interactions. It's
not 50 million people who click on the
link to check it out. It's just
impressions.
just impressions, which is like
notoriously
one of the easiest or maybe worst um
metrics for for success because um it's
pretty I mean you can boost posts, you
can do all kinds of things that might
give the impression that you're getting
more views, but like that doesn't
translate necessarily to either
engagement or actually swaying opinion
polls. I mean, if if um I imagine that's
like a metric that the firm proposed to
Israel as a way to measure their
success, as a way of showing that
they're probably having more impact than
they actually are. Um but but yeah, you
know, if you're if you're BB Netanyahu
and you're worried about the threat of
um of Gen Z um breaking in support for
Israel, you're seeing these polls. Um
then yeah, your your your metric of
success is not going to be impressions.
It's going to be okay, what's coming out
of, you know, Gallup or whatever. Um we
need to get that 9% number up.
Is there any indication at all or or did
you find any indication in the course of
your research that perhaps the American
taxpayer is ultimately paying for this
service?
>> I mean in a way people have pointed out
online that that it's sort of circular,
right? Because we've given Israel
>> so much money over the course of the
USIsrael relationship.
>> Um then you know I think what what is
the figure? something like 250 billion
over the last um 80 years or so. I think
it might might even be higher. Um and so
people have pointed out kind of that
circular nature, right? Where like
Israel that money flows from the US uh
to Israel and then Israel has uh this
public diplomacy budget um which it then
uses to try and influence how people
view Israel. I think um last year the
budget was $140 million for public
diplomacy and that includes anything
from this kind of work to financing
trips you know delegations to go to
Israel like um you know different people
that are that are prominent that that
might have a prominent voice on this
topic. Um and we've actually seen that
that Israel is is has increased that
budget. I mean they appropriated I think
140 million for fiscal year 2025 and
just last week herets reported that they
had increased that by $40 million just
through the end of this year. So you
know there is kind of a circular nature
where it goes from the US to Israel.
Israel then has this budget where they
spend a lot of money trying to influence
how other countries in particular the US
because they rely so heavily on US
support. Um and then that money kind of
trickles back into the US in a weird
way. And um a lot of these firms, these
kind of again ghost firms sort of cash
those checks.
>> Did you find any indication that
Brad Parcke's firm is not the only one
providing this kind of service? The
reason I ask is that the Israelis are
practically legendary
in
going after elected officials, for
example, who are not sufficiently
pro-Israel. they will primary the
daylights out of people and more often
than not they win.
I'm wondering if if it's not just this
kind of quiet behind the scenes
influencer driven propaganda
that we're seeing that it's something
tougher, something stronger, something
more in your face. Was there any
indication that it was something beyond
just what this company is doing?
>> Oh yeah. I mean I mean there are a lot
of different um
a lot of different things that that
Israel is doing. Um there there are a
number of firms that have registered
under Farah that that give far fewer
details around what they're doing for
Israel. Um and that's something that you
know me as a you know as a researcher
looking at these firms and knowing that
that Farah has requirements for their
transparency is it can be kind of
annoying. Um, but like there were there
were six different firms that registered
for Israel this this month and that a
lot of them just give indications like
there's one called um targeted
communications that that says that it's
doing media outreach on behalf of of
Israel. There's another one called
Genesis 2021. Um, and they don't give
many indication of what exactly they're
doing. Um, but there's one interesting
through line between all of these firms,
which is that it's being run um out of a
company um in Germany called Havos
Germany. And so, Havos has actually been
working for Israel for quite a long
time. I think initially it started
working for Israel in 2014.
Um, but it's although it didn't register
under Farah, I believe until 2018. Um
and and so this company in Germany has
been subcontracting all of these firms.
Um and so a lot of it is being run out
of there. Um so that's kind of the you
know the more we know about what Habas
Germany is is doing um the better. But
it seems like Israel has really
entrusted its um its strategy, its
social media strategy in reaching out to
these people. um you know whether that's
more surreptitious tactics behind the
scenes training the algorithms or the
more in-your-face stuff um like paying
influencers directly and all these
things. It seems like all of that runs
through this company.
>> Let me ask you I I know you're not a
lawyer. You're you're a researcher and a
and I would call you a journalist as
well. Um, but it I I am struck by
by Israel's
forwardness
in
trying to purchase
influencers. I I'll just come right out
and say it. Trying to purchase
influencers by by paying them uh per
post. Again, I know you're not an
attorney, but
is that legal? I mean technically these
influencers would be working on behalf
of the foreign government which would
then make them liable
>> to FRA regulations. They would have to
register as a a foreign agent.
>> Is that happening or is somehow getting
around this? No, I'm I'm I'm very glad
you asked that question because uh no,
I'm not a lawyer, but I have been
speaking to quite a few experts on Farah
um you know and they have told me that
because I had the same suspicion, you
know, um the that the influencers
themselves should be registering um
under Farah and they're not um they have
not registered under Farah. We don't
actually know who those influencers are.
We don't know who's getting paid to post
on behalf of Israel. Um and according to
the letter of the law, we should we
should know who those influencers are.
Um because if you are distributing
information on behalf of a foreign
government um in in in an intent to uh
influence either US political opinion or
policy makers, then the US public
deserves to know uh what the details of
the contract and who you are. I mean,
the same way Marjorie Taylor Green
actually pointed this out in a um a few
a couple of posts on on X and then also
I think she went on the One American
News show and talked to Matt Gates about
this, but she was pointing out that like
we have these these rules in place. Um
and when you're when you're scrolling
through X, when you're scrolling through
Instagram or Tik Tok, if you if a if an
influencer is promoting a brand, they
will usually make that clear. you know,
it'll usually say like hashtagbranddeal.
Um, if you're seeing sponsored content
on X, it'll say it'll mark it sponsored.
Um, and so we have these these rules in
place so that people can see can know
that that is not just organic content
that is appearing on their feed that
that it's that it's sponsored in some
way by a corporation that has interests
in promoting those materials. And um
Farah, you know, FHA is a law that was
created a very long time ago um in the
30s and it's been updated very few times
since then, but it does actually have
guidance. I mean, when you register
when you register under FHA, then it
gives you guidance on how you can comply
with FHA. And it even gives you guidance
on um how to to stay within the letter
of the law when posting on social media.
And it and it and it says that that you
should attach what's called a
conspicuous statement which is a
statement that basically says
um this information is being distributed
on behalf of X Y or Z. And so we
actually see this like when when other
registered foreign agents are posting on
X. Um, I I I'm I had an article about
this on Friday in which I'm I I
>> I brought up the example of Rod
Bgoyovich, the former Illinois governor.
He's currently a a registered foreign
agent of Republic of Serbsky, which is a
political entity in Bosnia. And when he
posts on X um on behalf of Republica
Serbska, he's he's very transparent
about it. you know, he he um follows the
letter of the law and he always says,
you know, whatever the content is, and
then he'll follow it up by saying, "By
the way, this is a a sponsored post by
Republica Serpska, just FYI." Um, and
that expectation there there's that
expectation for any registered foreign
agent that's distributing content on
behalf of a foreign government. So these
influencers, not only should they be
registering under Farah, but they should
also be mentioning within the contents
of their posts or on their profile
themselves that they are
producing this content, disseminating
this content on behalf of Israel. I have
to say too, this is not a difficult
process. It's specifically meant to be
an easy process. Back in 2008,
I won a small contract
uh with the the Abu Dhabi Chamber of
Commerce, right? And it was to write six
op-eds
uh promoting American business in Abu
Dhabi, American investment in Abu Dhabi.
So, I wrote these six articles and
placed them in different newspapers or
syndication services around the country.
And I went on to the Pharaoh website.
It's f a whatever.gov.
Uh so it's not
>> just in case anyone's listening.
>> Yeah. And um and I just went on and I
said my name and my address and my phone
number. I said that uh it was the the
contract was with the Abu Dhabi Chamber
of Commerce. This is how much they paid
me and this is what I did for the pay.
And you hit enter and it's done.
If you don't do that, the price can be
very high. You probably remember um a
Russian woman by the name of Maria
Buthina. Maria Bhina was a grad student
at American University. She considered
herself to be an exchange student,
although whether or not she was, I
think, is probably irrelevant. But
anyway, she was the co-founder of the
Russian version of the National Rifle
Association. So, she came to the United
States to go to school, but then reached
out to the NRA and other pro-second
amendment um organizations to try to
sort of forge relationships between
them. The Justice Department fell on her
head like a ton of bricks and they said,
"You're doing this on behalf of the
Russian government." She argued that she
wasn't and they convicted her of not
registering under Farah. So, what the
what the crime comes down to is that she
failed to fill out an internet form.
Right now, the federal sentencing
guidelines call for a sentence, and this
is a felony, by the way. Almost
everything is a felony for the federal
government. But anyway, the federal
sentencing guidelines call for a
sentence of 0 to six months.
She got 18 months, every day of which
was in solitary confinement.
Well, Nick, I haven't seen any articles
in the Washington Post or the New York
Times saying that pro-Israel influencers
or pro-Israel lobbyists have been
arrested and charged with violating the
Foreign Agents Registration Act. So,
what's up with that?
I think a lot of it has to do with the
the double standard that exists. um that
um you know another example out of
Russia was last year there were um there
were two RT employees that were um
indicted um because they were there was
this company called Tenant Media that
was a lot of people will be familiar
with this case but um they were secretly
paying influencers and they got indicted
because of it. Um, and you know, the
influencers say they they had no idea
the source of the um the money. And I
almost see this case with the
influencers being paid as sort of like
the the inverse of that where it's like
the influencers
um the influencers have to know, right?
Because this is a case in which there
the contract is now public. And and by
the way, for Farah, there is a a what's
called a a willfulness clause um that
they have to um kind of knowingly
violate Farah um that they have to know
like the source of the money for
instance. And I think it would be hard
for them not to know at this point
because the contract is is public.
There's been quite a bit of buzz around
them um around a cohort of influencers
that are being being paid by Israel. You
know, I'm I should say I'm not I'm not a
lawyer.
Um, so, so I'm not sure. I'm just
pontificating a little bit here, but um,
but yeah, you know, I think a lot of it
has to do with the the double standard
here. You know, that in one case it's
Russia and another case it's Israel. Um,
we've seen very few people even, you
know, especially elected officials
really want to talk about this. We saw
Marjorie Taylor Green um come out with a
public statement um noting that the the
influencers should be marking their
content as branded, but other than that,
it's been um very quiet from from
Capitol Hill on this.
>> Want to ask you too about um the
reaction to your piece. people on both
the left and the right uh read
the the Quincy um Institute website
every day. I I check it constantly. Um
it's it's a serious research-driven
um news source. So, what has the
reaction been to this piece?
>> The Well, the number one reaction has
been, "How do I get in on this cheddar?"
Like,
>> yes,
>> no joke. Right.
>> People are like, "Yeah, I I mean,
>> hey, free money. The Israelis are
handing out free money. How do I get
some?"
>> Exactly. 7K per post. I mean, people
will say anything for that kind of
money, right? Um,
>> so that's been that's that's been the
number one. And I and I and I wish I
could direct them to to um some kind of
application process or something. And
hey, if that firm had a website, maybe
they would more easily be able to get in
touch with them. Um, so that's been the
number one reaction. Uh but the the
other reaction I would say is just like
I mean people is is just outrage. I mean
outrage over the fact that um that that
this is happening and in particular we
don't know who those those influencers
are. Um so you know you see you see all
kinds of of reactions but I think um I
think people are starting to
pay attention to the ways in which
Israel is conducting a lot of a lot of
this outreach. Um and and by the way um
I'd like to just mention one other um
contract that Israel just um just
contracted uh a few days ago. It's it's
a firm that that I think just
illustrates a lot of this even further,
like the the extent to which they're
going to conduct this kind of outreach.
They hired a firm called Show Faith by
Works, which is California-based. Um,
and it's um it's a firm that's
conducting a lot of outreach to
Christians to it has a list of of dozens
and dozens I think over a hundred
different churches uh in in the American
Southwest.
And um a and what it's doing is that
it's geo fencing all of those churches
to put targeted which by the way
geofencing is a um it's a it's what it
is it basically isolates different
locations geographically so that if you
enter a particular area you are you
could be targeted with certain ads. It's
the same thing that like if you walk by
a um like an AT&T store or you're within
a mile of an AT&T store, you might see
more AT&T ads. Um and this firm was
hired on a $4 million contract to
geoence
um major churches
um with pro-Israel ads, with pro-Israel
content. Um, so if you are and they're
going to be tracing the attendees of
these churches. So a lot of churchgoers
and they're mostly evangelical churches
um are are now being tracked by Israel
and going to be inundated with with
pro-Israel um content. And
I mean the whole thing is kind of wild.
Another aspect of that contract is
there's going to be a like popup called
the October 7th experience in which um
people get to hear the stories of IDF
soldiers and talk about how hard it is
for them um to go after and this is a
direct quote quote unquote bad guys um
in conflict zones and really just hear
like a a very um pro-Israel perspective
on at a lot of these these churches um
and that story that has gotten very
little attention. Um, and you know, it
it just is another firm under Farah that
like it goes to show you the lengths to
which they're going to conduct this kind
of outreach across the US.
>> Yeah. Not to get too far a field, but
one of the things that has
both surprised me and and bothered me a
great deal is the viciferousness with
which American evangelicals and
evangelical churches have
unquestioningly supported Israel at at a
great cost to indigenous
uh Christian communities in Palestine.
Right. There have been there have been
Christians in Palestine for 2,000 years.
I mean, obviously it's it's where
Christianity originated. Uh there are
Palestinian Orthodox Christians,
Palestinian Catholics who are being
wiped out, literally wiped out. Their
homes being forcibly taken. They're
being expelled from the country. Most of
them, frankly, have moved to the United
States. And the evangelical churches are
perfectly happy to be party to that. And
they don't see the irony or the
hypocrisy that's involved in that kind
of a policy.
>> I just don't understand.
>> Yeah. And and all of that history that
you're mentioning from that is um is
absent from the the outreach that this
firm is conducting. Obviously, I mean,
they're presenting a very um they
describe it as like pro-Israel and not
just pro-Israel, but anti-Palestinian
talking points, and they're talking
about how, you know, Israel is is on
their side, and they're they're they're
erasing a lot of that history, frankly.
I mean, you don't see um mention of that
in in those documents.
>> What can you tell me about the view of
all of this uh from Capitol Hill? Is is
there really anybody that's interested
in Farah or the failure to register
under Farah? Is there anybody that's
interested in pursuing this to the next
level? For example, maybe looking at the
influencers and the money they're
taking.
>> It's possible. I I you know, I I would
just love to um you know, I've been
talking to a few staffers here and there
about this. Um, Marjorie Taylor Green is
the only one that's that's gone on
record about this. Um, but you know, I I
I absolutely think that that Capitol
Hill needs to take this seriously. I
mean, um, especially, you know, if you
are at the very least write a letter or
something, you know, I think that, um,
that that or at least some kind of
public statement saying that these
influencers need to be um, following the
letter of the law. I mean, Farah has
been um gutted in a lot of ways by the
Trump administration. Um you know, Pam
Bondi issued this memo at the start of
the Trump administration saying that
they were only going to enforce Farah in
cases of quote unquote traditional
espionage. Um but that doesn't negate
the fact that the influencers themselves
have to comply with Farah. I mean, Farah
is still the letter of the law. I mean,
it might not be traditional espionage.
I'm certainly not saying that they need
to be criminally charged or anything,
but they need to be like Farah needs to
send a letter to these to the firm um
saying, "Hey, by the way, you're missing
some information." Um there are a few
people um 14 to 18 to be specific um uh
short form registrants, foreign agents
that are missing from this contract. Um
so you know if if you're a member of
Congress and you're looking um you know
and you're concerned about the ways in
which foreign governments uh have
influence over the US um and concerned
about the especially lack of
transparency that we sometimes have um
about foreign government influence into
the US then this is like a slam dunk I
think that they should be engaging um in
um but you see a lot of silence and
complacency from people that don't
necessarily want to waste political
capital on something like this.
>> So, what's what's next on this and
what's next for you at the Quincy
Institute?
>> I'm going to keep um following this and
seeing um what else is out there. Um,
you know, I I expect at at the rate that
this is going that there are going to be
um more firms that that that register um
under under the forgration act for for
Israel. And um people can also uh you
know, I have a tip line open. I've got
an email in my my Twitter bio that um I
would love to hear from you if you have
any information about any of this kind
these kinds of stories. Um as for the
Quincy Institute, you know, we've got
bunch of different programs. I encourage
folks to check out our website. you
know, this kind of work is really just
um me and my team um you know, we we
write about defense policy,
military-industrial complex, the
influence industry, think tank funding,
those kinds of things. But we have other
programs that focus on uh the global
south, East Asia, Middle East, um and
also, you know, a um attempt to um take
on like UN Security Council reform and
things like that, envisioning what a
future international order could look
like. So, we have all th those kinds of
programs on our on our website. Um, and
then we've also got this this online
magazine that you mentioned, responsible
statecraftraft, which is kind of um
yeah, our online magazine that produces
a lot of more short form analysis and
reporting um than the long form
research. So, I encourage folks to to
check out those those two websites if
you haven't already.
Yeah, I happened to be in Los Angeles
last week uh for for a series of
podcasts.
And one of the things that struck me, it
was just kind of coincidence that that
three of the podcasters that I spoke
with over the course of the week were
not just Armenian, Armenian American,
but they were actually naturalized
American citizens from Armenia. and
independently of one another. All they
wanted to talk about was the Turks and
how the Turks are getting away with
murder and the Turks don't register
under Farah and the Turks uh have all
the best law firms and the Turks have
the best lobbying firms and then the
Armenians don't stand a chance against
the Turks. And I said, look, I I'm a I'm
a Greek citizen. I'm a dual US Greek
citizen. I said, "Greece has money and
is, you know, western in orientation and
it can't compete against the Turks."
Well, imagine having to compete against
the Israelis. It's just not possible.
There's not enough money, especially
when the deck is so stacked that it's
not just Israeli money we're talking
about here. It's probably American
taxpayer money as well. This is a tough
uphill fight
>> with a long way to go.
>> Yes.
Yeah.
>> Yeah. It's it's it's um it's a
it's a it's a battle between kind of
this like astrourf top-down campaign
coming out of Israel where they're
contracting this German company which is
then subcontracting a ton of different
firms um to produce this kind of content
against um what is this you know these
this like organic um
movement of people that are questioning
what is this historical ironclad
relationship between the US and Israel.
Um, and that's not to say of course
there are people that are are very
pro-Israel and have these kinds of of
views and and deny that you know
starvation is taking place that believe
that the Gaza humanitarian foundation is
doing a good job. all these things that
that those people exist very naturally
in the US as well of course but um but
yeah you know it especially when you
don't know which influencers are being
paid or who is being targeted by this it
becomes very difficult um to discern you
know what's organic and what's not and I
think that's um a difficulty in um
following this in in trying to parse out
you know what's organic and what's not.
>> And that's the rub right there. That's
the very reason why the Farah Statute
was written in the first place was
transparency and we're just not getting
it.
>> Yeah.
>> Well, Nick Cleveland Stout, uh, tell us
again what you're working on in the in
the near future at Responsible
Statecraft. We can send people to the,
uh, to the website.
>> All kinds of things. Um they'll have to
they'll have to wait and see. Um but
yeah, come go to Responsible Statecraft.
Uh I believe the URL is yeah,
responsible.org.
Um we're we're putting out at least a
few articles a day on there and um and
encourage folks to check it out and um
yeah, that's that's all I'll say about
that. I'll be a little bit cryptic.
>> Yeah, that's okay. Okay. Nick Cleveland
Stout is a research associate in the
democratizing foreign policy program at
the Quincsey Institute for Responsible
Statecraft. Previously he conducted
research on US Brazil relations as a
2023 Fulbright fellow at the federal
university of Santa Catarina with a
particular focus on the influence of
American think tanks in Brazil. He's
been published in of course uh
responsible statecraft the nation the
intercept the Brazilian report instick
and the national interest. And please
folks, do me the personal favor. If you
like the conversation or other
conversations that we've had, please
take uh just a second to subscribe,
share, like, tell your friends, leave a
comment, whatever makes you happy. So,
Nick, thanks for being with us. Ladies
and gentlemen, thanks for being with us.
We'll see you next time.